## ASHRAN HAIDER

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

+1 647 818-5812 • ch.ashran@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashranhaider • Toronto

# Summary

Experienced software developer with a solid seven-year track record since 2017, specializing in the development, design, and implementation of web applications. Proficient in utilizing technologies such as .NET Core, Angular, React, SQL, and Azure DevOps. My passion for coding dates back to university, and I have continuously sought self-improvement through dedicated research and self-learning.

## Skills

Active Directory, Agile Methodology, Angular, Database Design, API, SPA, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core, Asp.Net MVC, Azure, Azure Devops, bootstrap, CI/CD, MSSQL, Entity Framework, IIS, JQuery, MySQL, Oracle DB, reactjs, Scrum, SQL, T-SQL

# Soft Skills

Communication, Problem-solving, Teamwork and Collaboration, Adaptability, Time Management, Attention to detail, Leadership, Continuous Learning

# Education

#### Seneca College Markham

Graduate Certificate Cloud Architecture and Administration

01/2024 - 09/2024

COMSATS University Islamabad

B.Sc. in Computer Science

01/2013 - 01/2017

# Experience

### CONTOUR PVT LIMITED

Islamabad

## Full Stack Developer

03/2023 - 12/2023

- Development and maintenance of CRB Cunningham's software using Agile methodology.
- Collaboration with team from requirements to final delivery of software components.
- Active participation in software development using technologies such as C#, ASP.NET Core, React.js, and SQL Server.

DPL ISLAMABAD

# FULL STACK DEVELOPER

08/2021 - 03/2023

- Developed and delivered the successful product 'Asset Management System' single-handedly, later assuming the role of team lead for this project
- Used .NET 6, Entity Framework, MySQL at Backend and, Angular, bootstrap, angular material UI at frontend
- Used Active Directory for authentication of users

- · Used Azure DevOps CI/CD for fast deployments on multiple environments on IIS Server
- Took charge of project as senior software engineer and resolved issues of software architecture and environments creation in NLC Border terminal operating system
- As Senior Backend Engineer developed API using .NET 6, Oracle DB at backend in short time period and deployed beta version at NLC server
- · Actively taking part in requirements gathering meetings with client at NLC HQ

DPL Islamabad

#### Dot NET Core Developer | Full Stack Developer

04/2019 - 03/2021

- Participated as ASP.NET MVC Developer, contributed ideas, developed multiple features in admin portal of banking app of Arro Money Project.
- Used Active Directory for authentication of users
- Developed CI/CD pipelines for the development environment of the AgeEnvy project.
- Worked as full stack developer on multiple features of this healthcare project such as user feedback module, doctor public profile page optimization and improvements in various pages of the app using technologies of ASP.NET Core 2, Razor pages and Angular.

Fincon Services Islamabad

ASP.NET Developer

02/2018 - 04/2019

 Developed backend API for a survey android app using ASP.NET and SQL server as backend and web app for reporting based on survey data

COMSATS IT Center Islamabad

ASP.NET Developer

02/2017 - 10/2017

- Worked as junior developer on Comsats student portal using ASP.NET Webforms technology and SQL Server as backend
- Developed multiple forms in the application and worked on reporting pages